The following
content is provided
by MIT OpenCourseWare under
a Creative Commons license.
Additional information
about our license
and MIT OpenCourseWare
in general
is available at ocw.mit.edu.
PROFESSOR: So we
started last week
on the big topic for the rest
of the semester, optimization.
Maybe, can you close that
door or just partway, anyway.
Thanks.
Great.
That's perfect, just like that.
So, since it was
a few days ago, I
wanted to recap what I
did in the first lecture
about optimization, which was
to pick out the least squares
problem as a beautiful
model problem.
And I followed that through
-- the input is a matrix A,
rectangular, a right-hand
side b, probably measurements.
We would like to get A*u
equal b but we can't.
We got too many measurements.
We do the best possible,
which is the solution u
hat of this normal equation.
Then I rewrote the
normal equations -- well,
I also drew the picture that
you see over here on the left.
The picture that shows
the two optimization
problems at the same time.
Here is the vector b.
Here are all possible A*u's
-- this is the column space,
this is all A*u's.
The best A*u was the projection.
And the error e was
what we couldn't
get right, the part that's
perpendicular to the column
space we can't help.
It's the solution to
another projection problem.
e is the same -- of course,
it's the same over here --
as projecting b onto
this perpendicular line,
which is the line of all
vectors, A transpose e says --
what that says in words is e
is perpendicular to the columns
of A. I've drawn it the best
I could as a perpendicular
to the columns.
So that we have a
plane of columns --
this is like a
three by two matrix.
We have a plane with the two
columns and the perpendicular
line.
Then just near the end, I said
that it would be great to have
-- this model would be almost
all we need except it should
have one more matrix and
I called that matrix C.
I want just to show you
quickly where that comes.
So this is all section
7.1 of the notes,
except that these words
are not yet typed.
So they'll -- as
soon as possible,
an updated 7.1 will include
this, what I want to do.
Because I think it's the
very best introduction
I could give to these pair
of optimization problems.
You might think, who
needs optimization?
Your main activity might be
solving differential equations.
So, can I just take a time out
here because I happened to see
the homework, upcoming
-- I think it's 16.930,
so it's a course a
little bit like this,
only the first word in the
course title is "Advanced,"
and our first word is
"Introduction," but, of course,
it's the same course
or same stuff.
This is the homework
that I don't
think has even been assigned,
even been handed out yet.
But I just thought it's a
great example of a applied --
so that you see where
optimization appears
and what's involved.
So differential
equations are involved,
but also you got something
that you want to optimize.
So I just wrote it on this
board and I simplified it
a little over the homework
that they'll actually get.
So here's the problem.
We want a certain
distribution of heat.
So I could draw a picture.
We want a heat distribution,
for whatever reason,
that maybe goes like this
over the interval 0 to 1.
And what do we have
at our disposal
to get the heat to be that way?
Well, we've got sources of heat.
But we don't have a
continuous source,
we only have n
parameters to play with.
I mean, right away, you
recognize an optimization
problem.
We're trying to get this
function here, u_naught of x.
We're trying to
match a function,
but we've only got n parameters.
Those will be the
right-hand side.
So what we're allowed to choose,
we can put in little space
heaters, and we can turn them to
the temperatures we want to --
temperatures s_1, s_2, s_3.
That was probably
a stupid choice
to put an s_4 down there
because I don't even know
if negative heat is allowed.
Anyway, we wouldn't
want it if we're
aiming for that distribution.
Now you understand the
s's are not supposed
to match that u_naught.
The s's are the sources
of heat, and the u's
are the outputs,
the distribution,
and they are controlled by
a differential equation.
What we control is
the right-hand side
of the equation, but we
only control n parameters.
Then we have to
solve the equation
and find out what
distribution that gives.
So that's all like
differential equations,
we know how to do it.
It's one-dimensional in this
example, so straightforward.
But now comes the
optimization part.
We take this result
and we compare it
with the desired result.
So the actual result
from some source of heat
might be something like that.
We want this u of x,
the heat distribution
that we're actually
producing, to be as close
as possible to u_naught.
Close could mean
different things,
but if we measure closeness
in this integral square,
mean square sense, then we're
going to have nice problem.
In fact, we're going
to have a linear --
everything's linear right now.
Well, everything's
quadratic here,
so when we minimize it's going
to give us a linear equation
for the s's.
I just think that's
a good model problem.
A good model of
what we might do.
I think actually in the
problem to be assigned -- well,
it's not a big deal for us --
there is convection as well.
So this is a pure
diffusion problem, just
the second derivative.
We know very well
that if there was
a first derivative in there,
the stuff's convecting,
passing through the region.
So if I put on a
convective term, c*du/dx,
how does that
change the problem?
Not in a big, big major way,
but one thing we can guess
is that now that is not
a symmetric term, right.
We've seen the difference
between first differences
and second differences,
first derivatives
and second derivatives.
So now it's a little trickier
and it's not symmetric.
So somehow there will be a
primal problem, this one,
and there will be a adjoint
problem, dual problem,
perpendicular problem, whatever
name you want to give it,
just as there is in our
very first model over there.
So that's my little
quick look to kind of put
on the board one example
that I didn't invent,
that came from applications
and gives a sort of typical
of what you have to do.
You control an input,
you get an output,
so that's the analysis problem.
Find the output.
But then comes the
optimization problem --
make that output close to
something that you wish.
So what's the typical
algorithm going to do?
It's going to make
a choice of s,
it's going to solve the
analysis problem for the u,
it's going to look and
see what the error is,
it's going to figure out
probably the gradient somehow.
What's the steepest
way to make it closer?
That's going to lead
us to a change of s.
We use a change of s, the new
s, solve that, and iterate.
That would be a
typical algorithm.
We might be able to shortcut it
in a model problem like this.
But that's totally the
typical optimization idea,
is an analysis problem and
then figure out a gradient
to get a better source;
back to the analysis problem
with the new source.
What the algebra,
the math, has to do
is those two steps
of figuring out OK,
how do we improve
the error, how do we
reduce the error, what's
the steepest direction?
Somehow we got to
compute a derivative.
Actually, that's what
this month is about.
Derivatives that are not
just like the derivative
of x cube or something.
I often wondered
how many presidents
could take the derivative
of x cube and I'm not sure.
Anybody occur to
you who you could
count on being able to take
the derivative of x cubed?
I don't think the
current president
would know what it meant.
But I think Carter could
have done it, because he
went to the Naval Academy.
Jefferson was probably
-- he knew everything.
I don't know.
Anybody else has another
candidate they can tell me.
So there is our problem --
finding derivatives that would
be definitely beyond the
capacity of the White House.
Now I want to stay
with this model
a little more because
it's the perfect model.
So this was like model one,
unweighted ordinary least
squared, and it produced the
identity matrix in there.
And I mentioned last
time what I want to do,
the more general model
has another symmetric
positive-definite matrix in
there, but not necessarily i,
and it comes from
weighted least squares.
So that's what I'm
going to talk about.
So what are weighted
least squares?
Well, you've got these
measurements and you think they
maybe don't all -- maybe
they're not independent,
maybe they're not
equally reliable.
So you weight them by
how reliable they are.
A more reliable one you
would put a heavier weight
w on because you want
that to be more important.
So, you change to this problem.
But it looks
practically the same.
The only difference is A has
become W*A, b has become W*b.
So the equations will be
the same, but A is now W*A,
b is now W*b, and those
are the equations.
I guess I should call, just
to make clear that u is
a different u, that the best
u now depends on the choice
of weights, I should
really be calling that u --
somehow indicate that it
depends on the weight.
Now they key nice thing is
that if I write this out as A
transpose -- can you
just write this out?
You get the A transpose,
and the A is over here.
But what's in the middle?
What's this matrix C -- I jumped
the gun and called that matrix
in the middle C, but how
is it connected to W?
You can see it here as C
is W transpose W, right?
It's just sitting
there in the middle.
That's great that the fact that
the combination W transpose
W is all you need to know.
So we can forget W in favor
of -- I'll just put it here --
W transpose W is now
given the name C,
and this matrix is
symmetric positive definite.
So it's a great matrix and
it's exactly the one we want.
And this is exactly
the equation we want.
So if I go back to writing
it in this -- you know,
this was the equation.
You remember the point
that we could go directly
to one equation for
the best u, or we
could keep our options open
and have two equations that
led to the same one.
They're totally equivalent.
But the two equations will give
us not only u, but the error,
b minus A*u, as
an other unknown.
That's what we did up there.
So we had two equations,
and if we eliminated e,
we got to this.
Now I want to have
two equations,
and if I eliminate
e, I get to that.
So let me see what
those would be.
Well, here's one of them.
A transpose C*e is
zero -- you see,
that's the only
difference, really.
That the weighted
normal equation,
I just took A transpose C, and
then I took the b minus A*u
together, and this is
what I'm calling e.
So one way to do it is just
the new guy is just now e plus
A*u_W is still b.
But now a transpose C*e is zero.
Good deal.
I mean that's quite nice.
It isn't absolutely
perfect though,
because I've lost the symmetry.
I'm putting a C in there
and I don't really want it.
I want a C but I
don't want it there.
So, I just make a small change.
I'm going to introduce
a new unknown that I'll
call little w, apologies for
the fact that it's also a w,
it just happened to fit.
That'll be the C*e.
So I'm just calling
this a new name here.
So that now my e -- of
course, if I just invert,
e is C inverse w.
So now I'm just going to write
these equations with w instead
of e because I like it better.
So this equation is now A
transpose w equals zero.
This equation, the e is
disappeared in favor of C
inverse w plus A*u equals b.
So that's the system
that I really like.
That's the saddle point
system, the Kuhn-Tucker system,
the primal-dual system,
the fundamental system
of the whole subject in
this linear, matrix case.
We haven't got functions,
we got vectors,
and we've got symmetry,
and we've got linearity.
And we've got a saddle point
matrix that's now the S --
well, let me just
change it here.
It's just changed
to this, C inverse.
That's the fundamental
matrix of the whole subject.
So, S is the saddle
point matrix.
So I wanted to get that far.
You see that the whole picture
was elementary linear algebra.
Let me come back to the
elementary figure that
illustrates what's the geometry.
How was the geometry
affected by introducing
this guy W, this weighting
matrix, or the C equal W
transpose W?
Well, here was the
picture from last time.
A right-angled picture.
This was a right triangle.
This line was perpendicular
to that plane,
but not anymore now.
The second one, it's A
transpose C*e is zero.
That's still a line, but it's
not any longer perpendicular
to the -- this is
still all the A*u's.
This plane is still the
column space of all the A*u's.
We have the same b.
But you see the problem is
it lost its 90 degree angle.
Because the projection
is now projection on a --
it's now an oblique
projection, it's slanted.
This is the best A*u -- and if
I occasionally keep up-to-date
I'll put that u_W there.
There's still an error e, and
this is still a parallelogram
but it's not a
rectangle anymore.
Forgive my enthusiasm.
I'm sort of happy that the
picture and the algebra both
come out so neatly.
I totally agree
that at this point
I'm asking you to follow
a model without giving you
an application, and
that's one reason
I threw in this mention of
a specific application that
came from somewhere else.
But this is the picture there.
So I'll say one more
word about the picture.
I said that we lost
the right angle.
We lost perpendicularity,
and, of course,
literally speaking we did.
This is no longer -- this is
not a right angle anymore.
This is not a right
angle anymore.
It's not a right angle in the
usual meaning of right angles.
It is a right angle in
the inner product that's
associated with
C. In other words,
right angles here mean x
transpose y equals zero.
That's the idea
of a right angle,
right? x perpendicular
to y, and they
have different letters here.
Now over here I still have
perpendicular, but I don't --
this is not the right
inner product anymore.
It should be a weighted inner
product, weighted with this C
in the middle.
So that's really what
I mean by C-orthogonal.
Maybe I'll put those words down.
So this weighted thing is
-- if I can squeeze it,
I doubt if I can --
is C-orthogonality,
weighted orthogonality.
So let me circle
the whole thing.
The C is the W transpose W. Just
to say that we aren't giving up
on dot products
and perpendiculars
and good equations,
we're just changing them
by inserting C every time
in the inner product.
What it means is that this
is the natural inner product
for the particular problem.
This is the natural inner
product for Euclid, right?
But then from some
specific application
like this one or
a million others,
they have their own
natural inner product,
and the inner product for
that particular problem
would be one of these guys with
some kind of a matrix C showing
up.
So least squares and
weighted least squares,
that's my example one.
Now I'd like to give a second
example, a more mechanic --
will come closer to mechanics.
Because this is least
squares, statistics, algebra.
But let me put on the middle
board an application out
of mechanics.
It will be, say,
I'll make it small
and just a couple of springs
with a mass between them
and fixed at both ends.
So this spring extends
by some amount.
This spring extends
There's a force on this mass.
So there's a force on this
mass, maybe just gravity, f.
That's the external force
from the mass that's
here in between the springs.
Then, also acting on that
mass are spring forces.
This spring is
pulling it up, right?
There's a spring force, w_1.
Here, do you want me
to draw -- really,
which direction is this?
I'm going to draw it this way
just to show the w_2 drawn that
way would actually be negative,
because I think that this
spring would get
compressed, right --
this mass is pushing it down.
This spring would be
under compression.
It would be pushing
the mass back up.
So the w_2 in that
picture would be negative.
So this w_1 will actually
be positive and go
the way the arrow is showing.
This w_2 would
actually be negative
and go not the way
the arrow is showing.
But what's the -- oh, what
equations have we got then?
What's our optimization problem?
Well actually, we have a choice.
We could work with
equations, period.
Actually, one of the
equations is pretty obvious.
This mass is in equilibrium.
So w_1 is equal to w_2 plus f.
So it doesn't move.
Or you might prefer me to write
it, I would rather write it,
with w's on one side and
source terms on the other.
So that's the
equilibrium equation.
So what decides-- we want
to know what these w's are,
and these springs are extended.
So that first spring is
extended by an amount e_1,
and this second spring is
extended by an amount e_2.
Stretched or compressed.
e_1 is probably going
to be positive here --
that spring's going
to be stretched.
This spring is going to be
compressed, so that e_2 is
probably going to be negative.
What's the mechanics here?
Well, I can state it
two ways, as I said.
I can state the mechanics
in terms of equations --
force and stretching,
elastic constant.
That's how we did it in
the first semester, 18.085.
It's a little clearer because
simple equation, Hooke's law.
Or I can state the problem
as a minimization of energy.
That's what I want
to do today in 18.06.
So I want to minimize -- 18.086.
I want to minimize
the total energy,
the energy in these springs.
Subject to the constraint --
this constraint, equilibrium.
So that's the
optimization statement
of the mechanical problem.
Well, I guess all that
remains is -- well, I guess,
what remains?
First of all, I need an
expression for this energy.
If the springs are
governed by Hooke's law,
then it'll be pretty simple.
If they're real springs that
don't quite obey Hooke's law
then there'll be non--
there'll be fourth-degree,
sixth-degree, whatever,
terms in the energy.
It's like the energy in the
first spring plus the energy
in the second spring, anyway.
E in the first spring, and the
energy in the second spring,
and, of course, the two springs
could have different spring
constants.
So those E's -- I'll make
life easy in solving,
if I choose Hooke's law, if I
choose the energy to be just
a square.
The constraint is linear, so
that'll be the model problem.
And actually, that'll be the
kind of problem I've got here.
One reason for introducing a
new example was to get some
mechanics into the lecture,
but also to get a problem where
we're doing a minimization
but we've got a condition
on the w's.
And the question is how
do you find a minimum?
You can't just set derivatives
of the energy to zero.
You would discover w_1
equal w_2 equals zero.
Nothing happening.
That would be the minimum.
But that minimum is
ruled out, that solution
is ruled out because we
have this constraint.
We've got to balance
the external force.
So this is the question
and you'll maybe
have met this question in other
courses, but it's essential.
How do you deal with minimizing
when there's a constraint?
I guess, in some way,
we had it over here.
We were minimizing something
-- well, the minimum would be,
take u equal u_naught.
But no, there was
a constraint that u
had to satisfy a certain
equilibrium equation.
Here it was a
differential equation
so that problem is a
little harder than this one
where the equation is just
discrete, one simple equation.
So how are you going to do it?
Well, actually the
quickest way would be --
that's such an easy constraint
that I could say hey,
w_2 is w_1 minus f.
So I could just, if I
wanted to really like
shortcut this whole
lecture, I could
say well, w_2 is w_1 minus f.
Now I've accounted
for the constraint.
I've removed w_2
from the problem.
I have a minimization,
an ordinary minimization
with an unknown w_1.
I take the derivative.
I solve derivative equals zero.
I find w_1, then I go
back, I get that w_2.
That's the fast way.
Of course, gets
the right answer.
But there's another way that in
the end turns out to be better.
It's not necessarily better
for this simple problem,
but it's better for
the general approach
to constrained optimization.
So I'm going to not do the
simple deal of solving for w_2,
but I'm going to keep
the constraint around.
It's the idea of
Lagrange multipliers.
You've heard those words
and probably seen it happen.
So what is Lagrange multiplier?
What is Lagrange's idea?
Lagrange's idea is -- he
constructs a function of w,
to work with, which
is the same energy.
But he's going to
include a multiplier.
Now the next question
is what letter shall
I use for that multiplier,
Lagrange's multiplier.
Books on optimization
often call it lambda --
lambda's sort of,
like, for Lagrange.
So, Lagrange obviously wasn't
Greek, but anyway -- close.
Lambda for us always
means eigenvalue --
for me always means eigenvalue.
So I'm reluctant to use lambda.
And sometimes in books on
economics, which is doing this
all the time, the
multiplier's called pi
because it turns
out to be a price.
But let me use u for
the Lagrange multiplier.
So that'll be the
Lagrange multiplier.
So what do I do with it?
I multiply this equation by
u and I build it in to this.
So this thing is this part --
I'll just copy that down there
-- plus or minus,
depending what I want,
depending which sign I want to
end up with, u, the multiplier,
times the constraint
-- w_1 minus w_2 --
let me put it like that.
So the constraint is
that this should be zero.
So you can say I
haven't added anything.
I've added zero.
But that will only
be true at the end
when I have a
specific w_1 and w_2.
Right now what I've done is
I've built in the constraint
into the function.
Lagrange's brilliant idea was
that now I've got a function
that I can -- whose
derivatives I can take.
I could set the
derivatives to zero.
dL/dw_1 is going to be zero.
dL/dw_2 is going to be zero.
And dL/du is going to be zero.
So we got now three
equations, three unknowns.
Instead of going
from two to one,
we've gone from two up to three.
But it's so much more systematic
that it's the right thing
to do.
What is this last equation?
What's the u derivative
of this expression?
Well, u doesn't appear here,
the derivative is just w_1 --
this just leads us to
w_1 minus w_2 minus f,
which is the constraint
that we wanted.
So the constraint is
showing up as this equation.
Just the way the
constraint showed up
as this equation here.
I guess what I want to say
is when I wrote this down,
when we did this
first example, I
didn't say here's
the constraint.
I mean that equation
kind of came out
from the normal equations here.
So what we're doing new here
is we're starting with --
the constraint equation is
sort of part of the mechanics
and we're asking the question:
how do I deal with it?
Here it came out
of the geometry,
so it wasn't there
at the beginning,
so we didn't have to say: how
do we deal with this equation?
It just emerged.
Here it's really forced
on us right away.
So anyway, we've still got
to figure out the derivatives
of those, and I guess I do have
to finally now say what choice
-- yeah.
So this is -- what is this,
the derivative of E_1 minus u.
If I take the w_1 derivative,
I've got the derivative of E_1
with respect to w_1.
Then w1 doesn't appear
there but it appears here,
so it's minus u.
This would be the derivative
of E_2 with respect to w_2,
that second spring minus
-- oh maybe plus the u.
Well, those are the
three equations.
Let me move now to
the linear case,
just so we see the
beautiful pattern.
So if I make the
equations linear, what's
the energy in a
Hooke's law spring
here if the extension is e_1 and
if it produces a force of w_1,
I want to know what
is this E_1 here.
So let me just
remember Hooke's law.
I think Hooke's law
would say that -- well,
there's some elastic
constant c_1,
so there's a c_1 and a c_2
that tell us how hard or soft
the springs are.
So these are physical constants.
If I remember
right, the energy --
so I'm going to erase a little
here just to -- well no.
So what is the energy
in that first spring?
You remember, there's a
1/2 of an c_1 e_1 squared.
That's the energy in a
spring with constant c_1
and the stretch e_1.
But now, I really want
it not in terms of e_1,
I want it in terms of w_1,
just the way I did here.
I've got to do the
same thing here.
I want to get to w, because the
constraint is in terms of w.
What does Hooke's law say?
Hooke's law says w equals c*e,
that's Hooke, Hooke's law.
The force is the elastic
constant times the stretch.
So in place of the
e, I have w over c.
So this is 1/2 -- e_1 squared
will be w_1 squared over c_1
squared, and then a c_1 cancels
-- that's what it looks like.
I guess I'm certainly
happy to see that I'm
coming up with c inverse.
This c is showing up
in the denominator,
and that's exactly the --
so this is what I mean,
this is what I
want for my energy,
is a 1/2 w_1 squared over c_1,
and a 1/2 w_2 squared over c_2,
and now I was doing a minus sign
because that kind of goes well
with mechanics where a plus
sign would go well with all
the other applications.
So now I've got explicit energy.
So now I can say what
this thing really --
the derivative with
respect to w_1.
OK.
The derivative with respect
to w_1 is just w_1 over c_1.
Is that what I'm getting?
This is zero.
This says w_2 over
c_2 minus u is zero,
and this one says w_1
minus w_2 equals f.
Our three equations.
Yes, so I will kill these equal
signs and just look at -- oh,
that's a plus.
We've got our saddle
point matrix again.
That's the nice thing here.
This is a problem with
a three by three matrix,
with three unknowns,
w_1, w_2, and u.
With right-hand sides
zero, zero, and f.
And with what matrix?
That looks like a 1 over
c_1, zero, and a minus 1.
This looks like zero, a
1 over c_2 and a plus 1.
This looks like --
oh, wait a minute.
I don't want this.
w_1 minus w_2 equal f.
I can live with 1
and minus 1 there,
but it's not really
what I wanted.
I wanted the signs to --
you know what I want here.
I want the transpose of
that to be here, and zero
to be in that block.
So that's what my saddle
point matrix would look like.
Well, let me just say that
I could live with either.
I was aiming for this one
because it's symmetric.
But a lot of people would
rather have the opposite signs
and have the 1, minus 1 there.
I don't care which
sign f has, of course.
Some people these days are
liking this form better
because then it has
a symmetric part
and an anti-symmetric part.
I mean the thing
is, at some point
we're going to get problems
like this with thousands
of unknowns, and
we're going to think
how do we solve them and
maybe some iteration.
So we might want the matrix to
be symmetric but indefinite,
or we might want a positive
definite, symmetric part
and an anti-symmetric part.
What we can't have is
positive definite symmetric.
That's like asking for
what can't happen here.
The combination of the problems
is producing a saddle point
and we can play with that sign,
but we can't make that zero
something -- oh,
we could, actually.
What I was going to say is we
can't make that zero something
different, but you could.
That would be a
possible way to --
it's another way people thought
of of solving these problems,
is artificially throw
in a big number there,
or even a small number, and
push things towards positive.
Anyway, my purpose today
is essentially completed,
that we're getting out of
a physical application,
after I linearized and it
became a linear equation
and it had that
saddle point form.
So, saddle point form here,
saddle point form here,
saddle point forms everywhere.
I mean we'll have
the saddle point
forms for differential
equations,
as well as for matrix equations.
So those are the examples
to sort of hang on to,
and it's section 7.1 that
has a big part of it.
Ah -- I always have
one last thing to say.
What's the meaning of u?
So, u was a Lagrange multiplier.
Lagrange just like
helped us out by saying
OK, deal with constraints by
using one of my multipliers.
But the point is that
the multiplier always
has a real meaning.
I mention prices before.
Here, what's the meaning of u?
What's the physical meaning
of the Lagrange multiplier.
It turns out to be the
displacement of the mass.
It's the dual variable, so it
always has some interpretation.
In this case, with
mechanics it's
the amount the mass comes
down when the force acts.
What's more, it also has a
derivative interpretation.
Turns out -- I'll
just put turns out --
that the Lagrange multiplier u
turns out to be the derivative
of the minimum energy in
the system with respect
to the source term.
It's the sensitivity
of the problem somehow.
I'll just use sensitivity.
You often want to know -- it's
actually this quantity that we
need over there.
We want to know how much
does the answer depend
on the source, and that's what
the Lagrange multiplier tells
us.
So, if I computed the solution
here, so the notes do this --
maybe I'll leave
this for the notes.
The notes solve
this little problem.
That's easy to do.
They figure out what the
energy is in the springs.
It depends on the
right-hand side
f, which is just a number here.
The energy turns
out to be quadratic.
You can take its derivative
and you find out that it's u.
So that Lagrange multiplier,
that's really a key message,
is an important
quantity in itself.
Here it happens to
mean displacement,
which is obviously
crucial quantity,
and in general it
tells us the change
in the minimum
energy with respect
to a change in the input.
And sensitivity's a natural
word to use for that.
So that's a final
word about -- well,
a near to final word about
Lagrange multipliers.
So I'll see you Wednesday
and by that time
I'll know more
about the projects
and we'll be moving
onward with optimization.
Good.
Thanks.